Guide to the Administrative Papers of Chancellor George Bugliarello RG.007
Poly Archives at the Bern Dibner Library of Science and Technology, NYU Libraries
- Series III: Publications and Manuscripts, 4342
  - Subseries A: Publications and Reports (#3-#326, M, N), 3124
    - #116 - Bugliarello, G., "Educational Technology: The Decade Ahead," in "Frontiers in Education," Proceedings of the 1973 Purdue Symposium of the ASEE., 3215 (Box 28, Folder 91)
    - #117 - Bugliarello, G. and F.J. Gunther, "Toward a Science Policy for Computers in Water Resources: Trends and Issues." Proceedings, First World Congress on Water Resources, International Water Resources Association, Chicago, Sept. 1973., 1973 September; 3216 (Box 28, Folder 92)
    - #118 - Bugliarello, G., "From Notched Sticks to Knowledge Cells--One of Today's Mathematical Frontiers for the Engineer," Proceedings, Conference on the Applications of Undergraduate Mathematics, June 1973. Georgia Institute of Technology., 1973 June; 3217 (Box 28, Folder 93)
    - #120 - Bugliarello, G., "Technological Forecasting and Innovation," Proceedings, Conference on Technology and Labor in Transportation, University of Illinois at Chicago Circle, May, 1973., 1973 May; 3218 (Box 28, Folder 94)
    - #121 - Bugliarello, G., "The Engineer and the Historian," Proceedings, 1st International Conference on the History and Philosophy of Technology, University of Illinois at Chicago Circle, 1973 May; 5589 (Box 28, Folder 95)
    - #122 - Bugliarello, G. and F.J. Gunther, "The Evolution of Computer Systems in Water Resources Technology," Proceedings, Conference on a Decade of Progress in Water Resources, March 26-27, 1974, University of Illinois Urbana-Champaign., 1974 March; 3219 (Box 28, Folder 96)
    - #124 - Bugliarello, G. and H. Rouse, "Impressions of the People's Republic of China: Engineering Education," Mechanical Engineering, April 1975, 1975 April; 3220 (Box 28, Folder 97)
    - #125 - Bugliarello, G., "The University: How Neutral is Neutral?", Proceedings of the Symposium on the Responsible Use and Misuse of Scientific Data, 1975 Annual Meeting of the American Association for the Advancement of Science, Jan. 26, 1975., 1975 January; 3221 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - #126 - Bugliarello, G., "Let Us Not Give Up Our Dreams," (Guest Editorial) Experimental Mechanics, Sept. 1975., 1975 September; 3222 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - #127 - Bugliarello, G., "Social Values, Technology and Public Engineering Systems," Proceedings, ASCE Specialty Conference, June 1975, SUNY at Buffalo, New York., 1975 June; 3223 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - #128 - Bugliarello, G., "The Translation of Research Results into Practice," Proceedings, ASCE Specialty Conference, Environmental Impact of Irrigation and Drainage, Ottawa, Canada, July 21-23, 1976., 1976 July; 3224 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - #129 - Bugliarello, G., "The Emergence of Social Technology," Proceedings, International Symposium on Freight Pipelines, Washington, D.C., Dec. 1976, 1976 December; 3225 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - #130 - Bugliarello, G., et al, "People's Republic of China--A Look Inside," Civil Engineering, Journal of ASCE, January 1977, pp. 61-65., 1977 January; 3226 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - #131 - Bugliarello, G., "Biofluidmechanics: Quo Vadimus?," 1976 ALZA Lecture, Annals of Biomedical Engineering, Vol. 5, #3, Sept. 1977., 1977 September; 3227 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - #132 - Bugliarello, G., "A Technological Magistrature," The Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, January 1978, Vol. 34, #1., 1978 January; 3228 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - #133 - Bugliarello, G., "The Biosoma: The Coming Together of Man, Society and Machines," Chief Executive, July 1978, Vol. 5, pp. 34-36., 1978 July; 3229 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - #134 - Bugliarello, G., "Coating Technology--An Outsider's View of the Industry," American Paint and Coatings Journal, June 14, 1978., 1978 June; 3230 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - #135 - Bugliarello, G., "Challenges to the Engineer Who Manages--Expanding Your Research Capabilities," Electronic Design, Vol. 25, #12, June 7, 1978., 1978 June; 3231 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - #136 - Hung, T-K, R. Skalak, G. Bugliarello, Y.K. Lieu, D.J. Patel and M.S. Albin, "Perspectives in Biomechanics Research and Education for the Next Decade," Journal of the Engineering Mechanics Division, Proceedings of the ASCE, Vol. 104, No. EMI, Feb. 1978, pps. 3-9., 1978 February; 3232 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - #137- Hung, T-C, T-K Hung and G. Bugliarello, "Blood Flow in Straight and Curved Capillary Glass Tubes," Journal of Biomechanics, 1979., 3233 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - #138 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering Education for the 21st Century, To Respond To the Needs of Space Systems Engineering," The Future U.S. Space Programs, Advances in the Astronautical Sciences, Vol. 38, 1979, pps. 829-839., 3234 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - #139 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and Society: It's Time to Wake Up to the Problem," Proceedings, Conference on the Use of Media-Based Materials by Professional Societies in Continuing Education, New York, Sept. 28-29, 1978, pp. 3-6., 1978 September; 3235 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - #140 - Hung, T-K, G. Bugliarello and C.E. Quevedo, "Basic Biomechanics Equations for Cardiovascular Flow," Advances in Cardiovascular Physics, Vol. 1, pp. 47-101., Undated; 3236 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - #141- Bugliarello, G., "Industry and the University," Proceedings, First Midland Conference on Advances in Chemical Science and Technology, Sponsored by Dow Chemical Company, Oct. 16-17, 1979, pp. 153-170., 1979 October; 3237 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - #142 - Bugliarello, G., "Innovation and R&D: Issues and Challenges," Corporate Strategies for Growth, CDA 35th Annual Meeting, March 5-7, 1979, pp. 65-70, 1979 March; 3238 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - #143 - Bugliarello, G., Book Review ISIS, 70:2:252 (1979), Philip L. Bereano's Book, Technology as a Social and Political Phenomenon., 3239 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - #144 - Bugliarello, G., "Technological Universities: An Untapped Resource," Guest Editorial, The National Real Estate Investor, Feb. 1980, p. 28., 1980 February; 3240 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - #145 - Bugliarello, G., "Alternate Energy Sources--A Socio-Technological View," Proceedings, International Conference on Alternative Energy and the Offer of the Sun and the Sea, Milan, Italy, April 20, 1980, pp. 442- 461., 1980 April; 3241 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - #146 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering: The Advent of Metabiology," Proceedings, Symposium on Engineering and the Eighties, University of California, Berkeley, Calif. June 6, 1980, pp. 60-85., 1980 June; 3242 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - #147 - Bugliarello, G. and G.M. Yanizeski, "Some Phenomenological Characteristics of the Laminar Flow of Neutrally Buoyant Particles in Hele- Shaw," Biorheology, Vol. 18, pp. 331-346, 1981., 3243 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - #148 - Hung, T-C, T-K Hung and G. Bugliarello, "Blood Flow in Capillary Tubes: Curvature and Gravity Effects," Biorheology, Vol. 17, pp. 331- 342, 1980., 3244 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - #149 - Bugliarello, G., "The Role of the University Assisting Industry in the Fulfillment of National and Regional Needs," Technological Development in Nigeria, Workshop on Technological Development in Nigeria, Third Press International, 1979, pps. 509-518., 3245 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - #150 - Wu, T.Y., J.F. Kennedy, G. Bugliarello, D.R.F. Harleman, W.W. Martin, R.E.A. Arndt, R.G. Dean, H. Brenner and T-K Hung, "Fluid Mechanics Research in 1986," Journal of the Engineering Mechanics Division, ASCE, Vol. 107, No. EM3, Proc. Paper 16326, June 1981, pp. 445- 454., 1981 June; 3246 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - #151 - Bugliarello, G., "Industria E Universita Negli Stati Uniti D'Ame¬rica," Il Veltro, September-December 1980, pp. 463-490., 1980 September-December; 3247 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - #152 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering: The Advent of Metabiology," Part I, Journal of Clinical Engineering, Vol. 6, No. 3, pp. 231-236, July- Sept. 1981., 1981 July-September; 3248 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - #153 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering: The Advent of Metabiology," Part II, Journal of Clinical Engineering, Vol. 6, No. 4, pp. 261-267, Oct.- Dec. 1981., 1981 October-December; 3249 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - #154 - Bugliarello, G. and M.A.K. Malik, "Engineering Education in Libya," Engineering Education, January 1982, pp. 306-309., 1982 January; 3250 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - #155 - Bugliarello, G., "International Concerns in Engineering Education," Engineering Education (G. Bugliarello, guest editor), January 1982, pp. 266-268., 1982 January; 3251 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - #156 – Bugliarello, G., "Engineering Schools and Space Technology," Proceedings, 1982 ASEE Annual Conference, pp. 806-808, June 1982., 1982 June; 3252 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - #157 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology," Enciclopedia del Novecento, Istituto dell' Enciclopedia Italiana Rome (in Italian), Vol. III, pp. 382-414., Undated; 3253 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - #158 - Bugliarello, G., "Science, High Technology and the Research Partnership--A View From a Technological University," AAAS Report VIII: Research and Development, FY1984, AAAS Colloquium on R&D Policy, Washington, D.C., March 1983, pp. 220-226., 1983 March; 3254 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - #159 - Bugliarello, G., "The Development of Urban Research Parks," Proceedings, 1983 ASEE Annual Conference, Vol. 3, pp. 964-65., 3255 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - #160 - Bugliarello, G., "The Generation of Knowledge in Advanced Countries," Technology In Society, Vol. 5, pp. 171-79, 1983, also appears in University-Industry Research Interactions, Herbert I. Fusfeld and Carmela S. Haklisch, eds., Pergamon Press, 1984, pp. 15-23., 3256 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - #161 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineers--The Essential Ingredient of the Metropolitan Region," Guest Editorial, Met Section News, American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Vol. 34, No. 4, April 1984., 1984 April; 3257 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - #162 - Bugliarello, G., "Health-Care Costs: Technology to the Rescue?," IEEE Spectrum, June, 1984, pp. 97-100., 1984 June; 3258 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - #163 - Bugliarello, G., "Cronache dagli Stati Uniti: Rapporti fra universita e industria" (Chronicle from the U.S.: Relations Between University and Industry), Economia Pubblica, Vol. 1-2, 1984, pp. 56-58., 3259 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - #164 - Bugliarello, G., "A Global Network Emerges: It Will Lead to 'Hyperintelligence,'" Science Digest, March 1984., 1984 March; 3260 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - #165 - Bugliarello, G., "Graduate Education in the Soviet Union," Proceedings, 1984 ASEE Annual Conference, Vol. II, (Lawrence P. Grayson, ed.), (1984) p.937., 3261 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - #166 - Bugliarello, G., "Microcomputers and Engineering Education," Proceedings, 1984 ASEE Annual Conference, Vol. III, (Lawrence P. Grayson, ed.), (1984) pp. 1179-1180., 3262 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - #167 - Bugliarello, G., "Hyperintelligence," The Futurist (December 1984) pp. 6-11., 1984 December; 3263 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - #168 - Bugliarello, G., "What Limitations on Professorial Relations with Industry?," Presented at the AAAS Annual Meeting, New York, (May 28, 1984) also appears as abstract in Resources in Education, April 1985, and in ERIC microfiche collection., 1984 May; 3264 (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - #169 - Bugliarello, G., "Civil Engineering, Wake Up to the Challenge!" (Guest Editorial), ASEE Division Newsletter, (November, 1984) pp. 2-4., 1984 November; 3265 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - #170 - Bugliarello, G., "Viewpoint: The State of Engineering Education: Foundation for the Future?", Designfax, (January, 1985) pp. 27-28., 1985 January; 3266 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - #171 - Bugliarello, G., "The Ups and Downs of Civil Engineering", The Transit of Chi Epsilon, (Fall 1984), Vol. 56, No. 2, pp. 12-16., 1984 Fall; 3267 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - #172 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and Economic Development", Metroeconomica, Vol XXXVI, No. 1, (February 1984), pp. 111-119., 1984 February; 3268 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - #173 - Bugliarello, G., "Educational Standards and the Technological University", Education on Trial, William Johnston, Ed., San Francisco: Institute for Contemporary Studies, 1985, pp. 247-253., 3269 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - #174 - Bugliarello, G., "Water Resources Education for the Third World," Introduction, Idro Tecnica, Vol. 6, November-December 1985, pp. 373-380., 1985 December; 3270 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - #175 - Bugliarello, G. and G. Schillinger, "Editors' Note," in "Technology and Philosophy," C. Mitcham, guest ed., (Special Series) in Technology In Society, Vol. 6, p. 187 (1984)., 3271 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - #176 - Bugliarello, G. and D. J. Hockney, "A New Liberal Arts Curriculum for the Age of Technology," The Bent of Tau Beta Pi, Fall '85, pp. 50- 52., 1985; 3272 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - #177 - Bugliarello, G. (co-author), "Reviews of National Science Policy, Greece," Organization for Economic Cooperation and Development, Paris, 1984., 3273 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - #178 - Bugliarello, G. (co-author), "Politiques Nationales de la Science et de LaTechnologie, Portugal," Paris, 1986, 3274 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - #179 - Bugliarello, G., "The Strategic Defense Initiative and the University," Partnership With Industry And Community, ASEE 1986 Conference Proceedings., 3275 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - #180 - Bugliarello, G., "Socio-Technology, A Quest for a New Discipline," Science, Technology & Society, Number 53, April 1986, pp. 2-5., 1986 April; 3276 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - #181 - Bugliarello, G., "Human Resources and Future Choices for Civil Engineering," ASCE Conference on Civil Engineering Education Proceedings, The Ohio State University, April 11, 1985, pp. 14-40., 1985 April; 3277 (Box 29, Folder 57)
    - #182 - Bugliarello, G., "Colleges and Universities Versus Schools: Shall the Twins Meet?" National Technology Literacy Conference, Baltimore, February 16, 1986., 1986 February; 3278 (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - #183 - Bugliarello, G., "Why American Industry Suffers," Management Review, September 1986, pp. 61 and 63., 1986 September; 3279 (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - #184 - Bugliarello, G., "Computers and Water Resources Education: A Projection," in Journal of Water Resources Planning and Management, Vol. 113, No. 4, July 1987, pp. 498-511., 1987 July; 3280 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - #185 - Bugliarello, G. and G. Schillinger, "Editor's Note," in "Science, Technology & Individual Responsibility," D. Hart, guest ed. (Special Issue), in Technology In Society, Vol. 8, p. 237 (1986)., 3281 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - #186 - Bugliarello, G., Discussion of "Il Futuro dell'Ingegneria Italiana" ("The Future of Italian Engineering") in OICE Collana "Studi e Convegni, Vol. 14 (Rome, July 1986), pp. 85-86., 1986 July; 3282 (Box 29, Folder 62)
    - #187 - Bugliarello, G., "Socio-Technology and Systems Analysis and Engineering," in Systems Science and Engineering in Water Management, Proceedings of an International Symposium in Rome, November 20-22, 1984, Accademia Nazionale dei Lincei (Rome, 1986), pp. 31-62., 3283 (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - #188 - Bugliarello, G., "Key to Technological Survival: Efficiency in Manufacturing & Product Realization," in 1987 ASEE Annual Conference Proceedings, Engineering Focuses on Excellence, p. 1886., 3284 (Box 29, Folder 64)
    - #189 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology Literacy - The Essential Task" (Opening remarks at the Second National Technology Literacy Conference, Washington, DC, February 6, 1987), Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 7, Nos. 1 & 2, 1987, pp. 1-2., 1987 February; 3285 (Box 29, Folder 65)
    - #190 - Bugliarello, G., "Toward Hyperintelligence: Development of a Global Network of Education, Information & Cooperation", in XVI Pacific Science Conference Proceedings (Seoul, 1987), pp. 164-174., 3286 (Box 29, Folder 66)
    - #191 - Bugliarello, G., "Our Faltering Flight: The Crisis in U.S. Engineering Schools", Higher Education & National Affairs, Vol. 37, No. 2 (February 15, 1988), p.7., 1988 February; 3287 (Box 29, Folder 67)
    - #192 - Bugliarello, G., "L'Importanza Delle Universita Americane Come Fonti Della Innovazione Tecnologica" ("The Importance of American Universities as Sources of Technological Innovation"), Meeting: Scienza Tecnologia E Innovazione Industriale L'Uomo e La Cultura Del 2000, No. 22-12, Nov. - Dec. 1987, pp. 46-47, 49., 1987 November-December; 3288 (Box 29, Folder 68)
    - #193 - Bugliarello, G., "Why Study Science and Engineering at a Private College?" Private Colleges and Universities: Science and Engineering Edition, 1989, pp. 18-20., 3289 (Box 29, Folder 69)
    - #194 - Bugliarello, G., "New York City: Global Information Center," OBD News, Vol. II, No. 3, Spring/Summer 1988, pp. 3-4., 3290 (Box 29, Folder 70)
    - #195 - Bugliarello, G., "Six-Figure Salaries For Engineering Professors," in 1988 ASEE Annual Conference Proceedings, Beginning a New Era in Engineering Education, pp. 506-508., 3291 (Box 29, Folder 71)
    - #196 - Bugliarello, G., "Education for the Changing Pace of Technology: The Need to Transcend Our Self-Imposed Boundaries," (presentation at the 1988 winter annual meeting of the American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Chicago) in Education for the Changing Pace of Technology, ed. T.P. Torda, ASME (New York, 1988), pp. 5-7., 3292 (Box 29, Folder 72)
    - #197 - Bugliarello, G., "Fluid Mechanics in Civil Engineering: The Crisis & the Opportunity," Civil Engineering, Vol. 58, No. 12, December 1988, p. 6., 1988 December; 3293 (Box 29, Folder 73)
    - #198 - Bugliarello, G., "Toward Hyperintelligence," Knowledge: Creation, Diffusion, Utilization, Vol. 10, No. l, September 1988, pp. 67-89., 1988 September; 3294 (Box 29, Folder 74)
    - #199 - Bugliarello, G., "The Science - Technology - Society Matrix," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 8, 1988, pp. 125-127., 3295 (Box 29, Folder 75)
    - #200 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and the Environment," Changing the Global Environment, ed. Botkin, Caswell, Estes, Orio, Academic Press, Inc., 1989, pp. 383-402., 3296 (Box 29, Folder 76)
    - #201 - Bugliarello, G., "Some Random Thoughts on STS," NASTS NEWS, Vol 2, No. 2, April 1989, pp. 1-2., 1989 April; 3297 (Box 29, Folder 77)
    - #202 - Bugliarello, G., "Youth in Engineering and Sciences Program (YES)," Education Partnerships for Work in the 21st Century: From Pilot to Policy, March 1989, pp. 17-18., 1989 March; 3298 (Box 29, Folder 78)
    - #203 - Bugliarello, G., "Bioengineering: Merging the Artifact and its Maker," Mechanical Engineering, Vol. 111, No. 9, September 1989, pp. 46-48., 1989 September; 3299 (Box 29, Folder 79)
    - #204 - Bugliarello, G., "Industrial Engineering - A Crucial Profession," IEEE Newsletter, Polytechnic University Student Chapter # 846, February 1989., 1989 February; 3300 (Box 29, Folder 80)
    - #205 - Bugliarello, G., "Hydraulic Engineering: Global Challenge," Journal of Hydraulic Engineering, Vol. 115, No. 7, July 1989, pp. 863-868., 1989 July; 3301 (Box 29, Folder 81)
    - #206 - Bugliarello, G., Science & Technology in New York City for the 21st Century: A Report by the Mayor's Commission for Science & Technology, Polytechnic Press, December 1989., 1989 December; 3302 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - #207 - Bugliarello, G., "The Genetic and Psychological Basis of Warfare as a Challenge to Scientific Research," Ethical Issues Associated with Scientific and Technological Research for the Military, ed. C. Mitcham and P. Siekevitz, Annals of the New York Academy of Sciences Vol. 577, 1989, pp. xv-xvi., 3303 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - #208 - Bugliarello, G. and A.G. Schillinger, Preface to "An International Dialogue on Science, Technology, and Society Education" in Technology In Society, vol. 11, no. 4 (1989), pp. 403-4., 3304 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - #209 - Bugliarello, G., "Un Tentativo di Sintesi" (An Attempt at Synthesizing), in Nuova Civilta delle Macchine, VII, 4 (28) (1989), pp. 44-48., 3305 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - #210 - Bugliarello, G., "Developing A High Tech Presence," in 1990: A New Decade -- A New Administration, Proceedings of the 23rd Annual One-Day Institute - New York City Council on Economic Education at Baruch College, New York, May, 1990., 3306 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - #211 - Bugliarello, G., "Hyperintelligence: Humankind's Next Evolutionary Step," in Rethinking the Curriculum Toward an Integrated, Interdisciplinary College Education, M.E. Clark and S.A. Wawrytko, eds., Greenwood Press, New York (1990), pp. 25-37., 3307 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - #212 - Bugliarello, G., "Empowering Citizens Through Technology Literacy," Bulletin of Science, Technology & Society, Vol. 10, 1990, pp. 187-190., 3308 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - #213 - Bugliarello, G., "Modeling: From Primitive Brains to Hyperintelligence," Mathematical Computer Modeling, Vol 14, 1990, pp. 1-3., 3309 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - #214 - Bugliarello, G., "Engineering and Its Social Function: A Current Assessment," in Engineering as a Social Enterprise, presentation at the 26th Annual Meeting Symposium of the National Academy of Engineering, NAE, 1990., 3310 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - #215 - Bugliarello, G., "Technology and the City." Symposium on the Mega-City and Mankind's Future: Population Growth and Policy Responses, United Nations University, Tokyo, 1990., 3311 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - #216 - Bugliarello, G., "The University - and Particularly the Technological University: Pragmatism and Beyond." In The Changing University. D. Zinberg, ed. Kluwer Academic Publishers, The Netherlands, 1991., 3312 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - #217 - Bugliarello, G., "New Trends in Resource Management," in New Trends on the Resource Management, Proceedings of the First Pacific Rim Conference on the Resource Management. National Chiao Tung University, Hsinchu, Taiwan. April 17-19, 1991, pp. 1-21., 1991 April; 3313 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - #218 - Bugliarello, G., "Philosophy of Technology, or the Quest for a 'Hominis ad Hominim ad Machinam Proportio.'" Stephen H. Cutcliffe, Steven L. Goldman, Manuel Medina and Jose Sanmartin, eds. New Worlds, New Technologies, New Ideas. Lehigh University Press, 1991., 3314 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - #219 - Bugliarello, G., "Metrotech as a Model of Economic and Community Development." Fostering a Technologically Adaptable Workforce. Proceedings of the New York State Legislative Commission on Science and Technology, Report No. 92-1. Albany, February 1992., 1992 February; 3315 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - #220 - Bugliarello, G., "The Future of Science." Speech presented at the ARCS Scholarship Awards Luncheon, New York, NY. Polytechnic Press, May 1991., 1991 May; 3316 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - #221 - Bugliarello, G., "L'Acqua: Prospettive per l'Anno 2000." (Water: Perspective for the Year 2000). (Summary) Scienze e Tecnica, Vol. 54, nn. 253-254, Sept.-Oct. 1991, pp. 7-8., 1991 September-October; 3317 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - #222 - Bugliarello, G., "Broad Issues in Science, Technology & Society." Technological Literacy Workshop Proceedings. Russel C. Jones, ed. National Science Foundation, Association of American Colleges, Accreditation Board for Engineering & Technology, 1991., 3318 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - #223 - Bugliarello, G., "How Long Will We Continue to Accept the Dismantling of Our Industry?" Keynote speech presented at the 1991 American Electronics Association University-Industry Conference, San Diego, CA. Polytechnic Press, Jan. 1992., 1992 January; 3319 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - #224 - Bugliarello, G., "The Educational System and New York," Metropolitan New York Business and Market Guide, New York Board of Trade. New York, NY, 1992., 3320 (Box 30, Folder 19)